I'm here to offer you a new way to think about my field,
今天来到这里，是想邀请大家 从一个新的角度来看待我熟悉的领域：
artificial intelligence.
人工智能。
I think the purpose of AI
我认为人工智能的目的，
is to empower humans with machine intelligence.
是要用机器智能 来增强人类的能力。
And as machines get smarter,
而随着机器变得更聪明，
we get smarter.
我们也会更聪明。
I call this "humanistic AI" --
我称这个为“人性化 AI”——
artificial intelligence designed to meet human needs
通过与 AI 合作并 强化人类的设计方式
by collaborating and augmenting people.
来满足人类的需求。
Now, today I'm happy to see
如今，我很高兴能看到
that the idea of an intelligent assistant
智能助理的这个想法
is mainstream.
能成为主流。
It's the well-accepted metaphor for the interface between humans and AI.
这象征了人类与 AI 之间的互动 已被广泛接受。
And the one I helped create is called Siri.
而其中一个我协助 创造的产品就是 Siri。
You know Siri.
各位都认识 Siri。
Siri is the thing that knows your intent
Siri 会知道你的意图，
and helps you do it for you,
并协助你
helps you get things done.
把一切搞定。
But what you might not know is that we designed Siri
但各位可能不知道， 当初我们在设计 Siri 时，
as humanistic AI,
就把它定位在“人性化 AI ”，
to augment people with a conversational interface
通过对话的方式来强化人类体验，
that made it possible for them to use mobile computing,
让使用行动计算成为可能，
regardless of who they were and their abilities.
不论他们是谁、 能力如何，都可以使用。
Now for most of us,
对我们大多数人而言，
the impact of this technology
这项技术带来的影响
is to make things a little bit easier to use.
是让东西更便于我们使用。
But for my friend Daniel,
但对我朋友Daniel而言，
the impact of the AI in these systems is a life changer.
这些系统中的AI功能 却改变了他的一生。
You see, Daniel is a really social guy,
Daniel是个很爱社交的人，
and he's blind and quadriplegic,
也是个四肢瘫痪的盲人，
which makes it hard to use those devices that we all take for granted.
我们认为理所当然的设备， 对他来说却很难用。
The last time I was at his house, his brother said,
上次我去他家，他哥哥说：
"Hang on a second, Daniel's not ready.
“等等，Daniel还没准备好。
He's on the phone with a woman he met online."
他正在和网上认识的女生打电话。”
I'm like, "That's cool, how'd he do it?"
我说：“不错啊，他怎么办到的？”
Well, Daniel uses Siri to manage his own social life --
事实上，Daniel用 Siri 来管理 他自己的社交生活——
his email, text and phone --
他的电子邮件、短信、电话——
without depending on his caregivers.
不用依赖他的照料人。
This is kind of interesting, right?
这挺有趣的，对吧？
The irony here is great.
不过也相当讽刺。
Here's the man whose relationship with AI
这个人与 AI 的关系
helps him have relationships with genuine human beings.
协助他与真正的人类建立了关系。
And this is humanistic AI.
这就是人性化的人工智能。
Another example with life-changing consequences
还有一个可以改变人生的例子，
is diagnosing cancer.
也就是癌症诊断。
When a doctor suspects cancer,
当医生怀疑你有癌症时，
they take a sample and send it to a pathologist,
他们会先取样交给病理学家，
who looks at it under a microscope.
病理学家再利用显微镜来看样本。
Now, pathologists look at hundreds of slides
病理学家每天要看 数百片的载玻片
and millions of cells every day.
及数百万个细胞。
So to support this task,
所以为了支援这项工作，
some researchers made an AI classifier.
有几位研究人员做出了一种 人工智能分类器。
Now, the classifier says, "Is this cancer or is this not cancer?"
现在，分类器已经会看着图片分辨：
looking at the pictures.
“这是不是癌症？”
The classifier was pretty good,
分类器挺厉害的，
but not as good as the person,
但没有人类那么厉害，
who got it right most of the time.
人类大部分都能判读正确。
But when they combine the ability of the machine and the human together,
但，当机器与人类的能力 结合在一起时，
accuracy went to 99.5 percent.
正确率可以达到 99.5%。
Adding that AI to a partnership eliminated 85 percent of the errors
加上人工智能的协作， 人类病理学家
that the human pathologist would have made working alone.
能减少个人判断时 85% 的错误。
That's a lot of cancer that would have otherwise gone untreated.
这其中很多的癌症患者， 当初就是因误判而耽搁了治疗。
Now, for the curious, it turns out
人类因为好奇的原因，
that the human was better at rejecting false positives,
比较擅长判断假阳性案例，
and the machine was better at recognizing those hard-to-spot cases.
而机器则比较擅长判断 难以辨别的案例。
But the lesson here isn't about which agent is better
但我们学到的并不是
at this image-classification task.
谁在图像分类上比较厉害。
Those things are changing every day.
那些东西每天都会变。
The lesson here
这里我们学到的是，
is that by combining the abilities of the human and machine,
通过结合人类与机器的能力，
it created a partnership that had superhuman performance.
其创造出的合作关系 会有超人般的表现。
And that is humanistic AI.
而这就是人性化的人工智能 。
Now let's look at another example
我们再举个例子，
with turbocharging performance.
这方面的进步也是突飞猛进。
This is design.
那就是“设计”。
Now, let's say you're an engineer.
假设你是个工程师，
You want to design a new frame for a drone.
想要设计一个新的无人机骨架。
You get out your favorite software tools, CAD tools,
你打开最爱的软件， 电脑绘图辅助工具（CAD），
and you enter the form and the materials, and then you analyze performance.
输入了外形和材料， 然后按下分析表现。
That gives you one design.
它只会跑出一种设计方案。
If you give those same tools to an AI,
如果你把这些工具拿给 AI 使用，
it can generate thousands of designs.
它会帮你跑出数千种设计。
This video by Autodesk is amazing.
这段Autodesk 的影片非常震撼。
This is real stuff.
这是真实案例。
So this transforms how we do design.
这就改变了我们设计的方式。
The human engineer now
现在，人类工程师
says what the design should achieve,
只要说出想要实现的设计，
and the machine says,
机器就会说：
"Here's the possibilities."
”有这些可能性方案。”
Now in her job, the engineer's job
现在，她作为工程师的工作，
is to pick the one that best meets the goals of the design,
就是选出一种最符合目标的设计，
which she knows as a human better than anyone else,
这是她身为人类最擅长的，
using human judgment and expertise.
用的就是人类的判断和专业知识。
In this case, the winning form
在这案例中，脱颖而出的设计
looks kind of like something nature would have designed,
像是自然界设计出来的，
minus a few million years of evolution
但这样的设计， 不需要几百万年的演化，
and all that unnecessary fur.
也不需有那些皮毛。
Now let's see where this idea of humanistic AI might lead us
我们现在来想想， 如果我们跟着人性化 AI 走，
if we follow it into the speculative beyond.
它会把我们带到哪些 意想不到的境界？
What's a kind of augmentation that we would all like to have?
我们想要实现哪些方面的强化？
Well, how about cognitive enhancement?
认知强化如何？
Instead of asking,
别再问：
"How smart can we make our machines?"
“我们能把机器做到多聪明？”
let's ask
而是要改问：
"How smart can our machines make us?"
“我们的机器能把我们变得多聪明？”
I mean, take memory for example.
举个例子，记忆。
Memory is the foundation of human intelligence.
记忆是人类智能的基础。
But human memory is famously flawed.
但人类的记忆力是出名的差。
We're great at telling stories,
我们很会说故事，
but not getting the details right.
但无法保证细节都是准确的。
And our memories -- they decay over time.
我们的记忆——会随时间衰退。
I mean, like, where did the '60s go, and can I go there, too?
比如，六十年代去哪了？ 我也能去那儿吗？
(Laughter)
（笑声）
But what if you could have a memory that was as good as computer memory,
但如果你能拥有和电脑 一样好的记忆力，
and was about your life?
而且这些记忆与你的人生有关， 那会如何呢？
What if you could remember every person you ever met,
如果你能记得 你见过的每一个人，
how to pronounce their name,
叫得出每一个人的名字，
their family details, their favorite sports,
家庭状况的细节， 他们最爱的运动，
the last conversation you had with them?
你和他们上次的对话，那会如何呢？
If you had this memory all your life,
如果你一生都有这样的记忆，
you could have the AI look at all the interactions
你就可以让人工智能 去看看你过去
you had with people over time
与人们的所有互动，
and help you reflect on the long arc of your relationships.
并协助你反思你的人际关系。
What if you could have the AI read everything you've ever read
如果我们能让人工智能去阅读 所有你阅读过的东西，
and listen to every song you've ever heard?
去听你听过的每首歌，会如何呢？
From the tiniest clue, it could help you retrieve
从最微小的线索， 它就能协助你找回
anything you've ever seen or heard before.
你以前看过或听过的任何东西。
Imagine what that would do for the ability to make new connections
想像一下，这对于 建立新连结以及
and form new ideas.
产生新点子的能力会有什么影响。
And what about our bodies?
那么，我们的身体呢？
What if we could remember the consequences of every food we eat,
如果我们能记得吃过的每样食物，
every pill we take,
每颗药物，
every all-nighter we pull?
记得每次熬夜的内容， 那会如何？
We could do our own science on our own data
我们可以用自己的资料 来做自己的科学，
about what makes us feel good and stay healthy.
找出什么会让我们 感觉很好并保持健康。
And imagine how this could revolutionize
想像一下，这会为我们管理
the way we manage allergies and chronic disease.
过敏及慢性病带来怎样的革命。
I believe that AI will make personal memory enhancement a reality.
我相信，人工智能能够 实现个人记忆的强化。
I can't say when or what form factors are involved,
我不知道何时或需要哪些机缘，
but I think it's inevitable,
但我认为它是一定会到来的，
because the very things that make AI successful today --
因为人工智能在当今 够成功的原因就是这些——
the availability of comprehensive data
唾手可得的综合性数据，
and the ability for machines to make sense of that data --
以及机器能从这些数据中 理解出意义的能力——
can be applied to the data of our lives.
能够被应用到我们生活中的数据上。
And those data are here today, available for all of us,
我们现今就已经能够 取得那些数据了，
because we lead digitally mediated lives,
因为我们可以直接用手机 或上网的方式，
in mobile and online.
将我们的生活与数字科技做连结。
In my view, a personal memory is a private memory.
依我所见，个人的记忆 是私人的记忆。
We get to choose what is and is not recalled and retained.
我们可以选择要或不要， 回忆或保留哪些记忆。
It's absolutely essential that this be kept very secure.
这种安全性绝对是有必要的。
Now for most of us,
对大部份人来说，
the impact of augmented personal memory
增强个人记忆所产生的影响会是：
will be a more improved mental gain,
可以获得心智上的成长，
maybe, hopefully, a bit more social grace.
或是希望可以有更好的社交能力。
But for the millions who suffer from Alzheimer's and dementia,
但对于数百万受阿兹海默症 及痴呆症折磨的人而言，
the difference that augmented memory could make
增加记忆能造成的改变
is a difference between a life of isolation
就是让那孤独的人生，
and a life of dignity and connection.
变成有尊严， 与生活保持连接的人生。
We are in the middle of a renaissance in artificial intelligence right now.
我们现在正处于人工智能 繁荣发展的时期当中，
I mean, in just the past few years,
仅仅在过去几年，
we're beginning to see solutions to AI problems
我们就开始看到 人工智能问题的解决方法，
that we have struggled with literally for decades:
而这在过去数十年来， 一直是无法解决的问题，比如：
speech understanding, text understanding,
口语理解，文字理解，
image understanding.
图像理解。
We have a choice in how we use this powerful technology.
我们可以选择要 如何使用这强大的技术。
We can choose to use AI to automate and compete with us,
我们可以选择用人工智能 来做自动化的工作，并与我们竞争，
or we can use AI to augment and collaborate with us,
或我们可以选择用人工智能 来做增强化的工作，并与我们合作，
to overcome our cognitive limitations
来克服我们的认知限制，
and to help us do what we want to do,
并协助我们去做我们想要做的事，
only better.
而且做得更好。
And as we discover new ways to give machines intelligence,
随着我们发掘出新的方式 来将智能赋予机器，
we can distribute that intelligence
我们可以把那种智能移转到
to all of the AI assistants in the world,
全世界所有的人工智能助理身上，
and therefore to every person, regardless of circumstance.
且不论如何，都要确保 每个人都能因此受惠。
And that is why,
那就是为什么
every time a machine gets smarter,
每次当机器变更得聪明，
we get smarter.
我们也会变得更睿智。
That is an AI worth spreading.
而这就是人工智能 值得推广的原因。
Thank you.
谢谢大家。
(Applause)
（掌声）